Register to the Enrico Batelli Papers
Yale University Music Library
Enrico Batelli Papers
1896-1944
MSS 92
Yale University Music Library
0.75
(2 boxes)
The Enrico Batelli Papers consist primarily of manuscript scores and parts for Batelli's original musical compositions and arrangements of music by other composers. The papers also contain manuscript and printed music by other composers, including several by Batelli's teacher, Paolo Serrao, plus a small number of biographical materials.
Batelli, Enrico
Badia, Luigi, 1819?-1899
Denza, Luigi, 1846-1922
De Leva, Enrico, 1867-1955
Serrao, Paolo, 1830-1907
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Unknown.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Biographical / Historical
Enrico Batelli was one of New Haven's leading musicians in the first half of the twentieth century. Born in Caserta, Italy in 1875 or 1876, he was trained at the Naples Conservatory. In 1902 Batelli came to the United States, and eventually decided to settle in New Haven, where he was active as a composer, conductor, organist, pianist, and teacher. He had a teaching studio at 890 Chapel Street in New Haven, and he worked at several local churches, culminating in a 38-year career as organist at St. John the Evangelist Roman Catholic Church at 79 Davenport Street. He died in New Haven on July 31, 1944.
Scope and Contents
The Enrico Batelli Papers consist primarily of manuscript scores and parts for Batelli's original musical compositions and arrangements of music by other composers. The papers also contain manuscript and printed music by other composers, including several by Batelli's teacher, Paolo Serrao, plus a small number of biographical materials.
Arrangement
Arranged in 2 series as follows: I. Music. II. Biographical Materials.
Choruses, sacred (mixed voices); Choruses, secular (mixed voices); Masses; Songs, Italian; Batelli, Enrico
- Music, 1889-1932; Series I
  - Music composed by Enrico Batelli, 1894-1932; Sub-Series I.A
    - [Alé, Alé, Alé!] Alé, Alé, Alé!: canzone del carnevale di Caserta / versi di V. Cimmaruta; musica di Enrico Batelli. – 1894., 1 ms. score (17 p.); 33 cm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General
      Copyist's ms. in ink.
      For voice and orchestra.
      On tp: Premiata al concorso musicale.
    - [Ave Maria, op. 16] Ave Maria, op. 16 / by Enrico Batelli., 1909; 1 ms. score (4 p.) + 1 ms. part (3 p.); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Holograph in ink, pencil, and colored pencil.
      For soprano or tenor with organ.
      Includes separate part for cello obligato.
      At end: New Haven, Conn., March 11th, 1909.
    - [Ave Maria, op. 16 (Sketches)], 4 ms. p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Holograph in pencil and colored pencil.
    - [Baiser] Un baiser = A kiss / words by L. Le Lasseur De Ranzay; English version by Isabella G. Parker; music by Enrico Batelli., 1 ms. score (5 p.); 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Holograph in ink and pencil.
      For baritone and piano.
    - [Cadenza], 43 p. of music; mostly 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Ms. in ink, pencil, and colored pencil.
      Vocal cadenzas for arias and songs, composed or copied by Batelli.
      Contents [partial]: Variations on a Mozart Air / [Adam?] – Fra Diavolo [Auber] – La Sonnambula / [Bellini] – Lucia di Lammermoor / [Donizetti] – None He Loves But Me / Eckert – Mireille / Gounod – Dinorah / [Meyerbeer] – Theme and Variations / Proch – [Barbiere di Siviglia / Rossini]
      Includes published editions of Donizetti and Proch arias.
    - [Chanson d'amour], 5 ms. p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      For piano.
    - [Easter Sunday] Easter Sunday / by Enrico Batelli., 1911; 3 ms. p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      At end: New Haven, April 4th, 1911.
      For string parts see [Piano music. Selections; arr.]
    - [Etude]Étude, op. 20, no. 1 / by Enrico Batelli., 6 ms. p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Holograph in ink.
    - [Fantasia militare; arr.] Ouverture: fantasia militare / l'accompamento di Enrico Batelli., 22 p. of music; 32 & 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Copyist's ms. and holograph in ink, pencil, and colored pencil.
      Arr. for piano solo, final 3 p. arr. for 2 pianos.
      Includes instrumental cues.
    - [Fedora] Fedora: alcuni pensieri per piano-forte / di Enrico Batelli., 1900; 10 ms. p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Based on themes from the opera Fedora by Umberto Giordano.
      At end: Caserta, Luglio 1900.
    - [Gioia della vittoria] La gioia della vittoria: marcia / di Enrico Batelli., 1903; 4 ms. p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Copyist's ms. in ink and pencil.
      On tp: All'amico Anto. A. Spinello (souvenir des jours 11 et 12 Juin 1903)
    - [Hail to America]
      See [Preludio sinfonico and chorus]
    - [Hosanna!] Hosanna!, 5 + 4 ms. parts (21 p. total); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Parts (in B-flat) for vlnI, vlnII, vla, vc, b.
      Parts (in G) for vlnI, vlnII, vla, vc.
      Different from the Hosanna section of the composer's Easter Sunday.
    - [Kyrie, mixed voices, organ, G major], 1 ms. score (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Lacks text.
    - [Kyrie, mixed voices, organ, G major (Sketches)], 1 ms. score (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - [Missa solemnis, no. 1] Missa solemnis: for four solo voices and chorus / by Enrico Batelli., 5 ms. parts (51 p. total); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Parts for vlnI, vlnII, vla, vc, b, including variant parts for bass.
    - [Missa solemnis, no. 1. Vocal score] Missa solemnis: for four solo voices and chorus with organ accompaniment / by Enrico Batelli., 1 ms. vocal score (29 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 16)
      On tp: Dedicated to St. John's R.C. Church's Choir of New Haven, Conn.
    - [Missa solemnis, no.1. Chorus parts] Missa solemnis / by Enrico Batelli., 4 ms. parts (56 p. total); 36 cm. (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Chorus parts for SA and TB, including solo sections and duets.
    - [Missa solemnis, no. 2] Second solemn mass / by Enrico Batelli., 12 ms. parts (101 p. total); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Parts for vlnI, vlnII, vla, vc, b. Additional parts (Gloria only) for fl, cl, cornet, tbn, campanelle, pno, org.
    - [Missa solemnis, no. 2. Chorus parts] Second solemn mass / by Enrico Batelli., 4 ms. parts (113 p. total); 33 cm. (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Chorus parts for SATB.
      Includes duplicate copies.
    - [O Jesu, o pastor bone] O Jesu, o pastor bone (Ti prego, o Madre pia) / Enrico Batelli., 1 ms. score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 20)
      For soprano, baritone, organ, and harp.
      Words in Latin and Italian.
    - [O salutaris hostia] O salutaris hostia: sacred duet for alto and baritone, with piano or organ accompaniment / Enrico Batelli., 1909; 1 ms. score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 21)
      At end: New Haven, Conn., April 1909.
    - [Occhi tuoi] Gli occhi tuoi: valzer per mandolino e piano / di Enrico Batelli., 1896; 1 ms. score (8 p.); 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 22)
      On tp: A mio angelo, Enrico.
      At end: Caserta, Luglio 1896.
    - [Pensiero elegiaco] Pensiero elegiaco per piano-forte / di E. Batelli. – New Haven., 3 ms. p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Holograph in pencil.
      On tp: In memoria d'il [illegible]
    - [Piano music. Selections; arr.] Easter Sunday [and] Silver wedding march (Poli's march) / by Enrico Batelli., 1911; 5 ms. parts (24 p. total); 34 & 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Parts for vlnI, vlnII, vla, vc, b.
      Duplicate part for b with some variants.
      On vlnI part: New Haven, 9 April 1911.
    - [Preludio sinfonico and chorus] Preludio sinfonico and chorus: "Hail to America" / by Enrico Batelli., 6 ms. parts (24 p. total); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Holograph in ink and colored pencil.
      Parts for pno, org, vlnI, vlnII, vla, vc.
    - [Preludio sinfonico and chorus. Vocal score] Preludio sinfonico and chorus: Hail to America / words by Dean B. Lyman, Jr.; music by Enrico Batelli., 1916; 1 ms. vocal score (7 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Arr. for chorus (SATB) and piano.
      At end: New Haven, Conn., May 9, 1916.
    - [Preludio sinfonico and chorus. Vocal score] Prelude and chorus: Hail to America / by Enrico Batelli., 1 ms. vocal score (8 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Holograph in pencil and ink.
    - [Preludio sinfonico and chorus. Vocal score] Hail to America: chorus for mixed voices., 1 ms. vocal score (5 p.); 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Hail to America refrain only, lacks all of Preludio sinfonico except for 7 mm.
      "Dedicated to the United States of America."
    - [Preludio sinfonico and chorus. Chorus parts] Hail to America / by E. Batelli., 1917; 4 ms. parts (11 p. total); various sizes. (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Choral parts for SATB.
      2 sets with possible variants.
      Includes ms. title page.
      On tp: copyrighted June 1917 by Enrio Batelli.
    - [Preludio sinfonico and chorus (Sketches)], 21 ms. p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - [Silver wedding march] Silver wedding march, op. 24 / by Enrico Batelli., 1910; 5 ms. p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 31)
      "To Mr. and Mrs. S. J. Poli (souvenir du jour 25/8, 1910)"
      At end: Enrico Batelli, #890 Chapel St., Room 35, New Haven, Conn.
    - [Song without words]
      See also: Programs. April 16, 1932. Dinner musical program in honor of Cavalier Joseph C. Johnson (4 p.)
    - [Song without words] Song without words: for violin and piano / by Enrico Batelli., 1932; 1 ms. score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 1, Folder 32)
      On tp: Written especially for and dedicated to Cavalier Joseph C. Johnson, New Haven, Conn., April 16, 1932.
    - [Song without words; arr.] Song without words: string quartet / by Enrico Batelli., 1932; 1 ms. score (3 p.) + 4 ms. parts (4 p. total); 32 & 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Parts for vlnI (may also be used with the piano score above), vlnII, va, vc.
      On tp: New Haven, Conn., April 1932.
    - [Tantum ergo, B-flat major] Tantum ergo / E. Batelli., 4 ms. scores (4 p. total); 33 cm. (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Each score marked and texted for a different choral part (SATB)
      Organ introduction of 3 mm., but no additional keyboard accompaniment.
    - [Tantum ergo, C major] Tantum ergo / music by Enrico Batelli., 1901; 2 ms. scores (12 p. total) + 1 ms part (4 p.); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 34)
      For chorus (SATB) and organ ad. lib.
      At end: Milano, 25 Giugno 1901.
      Part for organ, untexted.
    - [Tarantella, piano] Tarantelle, op. 18, no. 3 / by Enrico Batelli., 10 ms. p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 35)
      "To Mr. Rudolph Steinert."
      With a second copy, 12 p., on which the dedication is crossed out.
    - [Tempo di valzer] Tempo di valzer: quartetto per mandolino 1o, mandolino 2o, mandola in sol, e piano-forte / di Enrico Batelli., 1 ms. score (9 p.); 33 cm. (Box 1, Folder 36)
      On tp: Al Maggiore Berio Cavalier Giovanni in occasione del suo onomastico, Enrico Batelli.
    - [Triumphal march] Triumphal march / by Enrico Batelli. – [New Haven], c1929., 5 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 1, Folder 37)
      On tp: To Dr. William F. Verdi.
      2 copies.
    - [Triumphal march; arr.] Triumphal march / by Enrico Batelli., 1929; 1 ms. score (16 p.) + 12 ms. parts (32 p. total); 32 & 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 38)
      Copyist's ms. and holograph in ink and colored pencil.
      Parts for fl, cl, cornetI/II, tbn, timp, harp, pno, vlnI, vlnII, vla, vc, b.
      On tp: To Doctor William F. Verdi.
      At end: New Haven, Conn., March 10, 1929.
    - [Under the flag] Under the flag / by Enrico Batelli. (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Scope and Contents
      10 ms. parts (26 p. total); 35 cm.
      Parts for fl, cl, cornet, tbn, drum, vlnI, vlnII, vla, vc, b.
    - [Veni creator] Veni creator / by Enrico Batelli., 1912; 1 ms. score (3 p.); 34 cm. (Box 1, Folder 40)
      For chorus (SATB) chorus and organ.
      At end: New Haven, Conn., Saturday, 20 January 1812 [i.e. 1912]
    - [Vidi aquam] Vidi aquam: [for] four mixed voices / by Enrico Batelli., 1907; 1 ms. score (6 p.); 35 cm. (Box 1, Folder 41)
      For chorus (SATB) and organ.
      At end: New Haven, Conn., 29/3, 1907.
    - [Waltzes, mandolins (2), mandola, piano]
      See: [Tempo di Valzer]
    - [Yale!, Yale!, Yale!] Yale!, Yale!, Yale!: a song of New Haven / words by Ella Wheeler Wilcox; music by Enrico Batelli. -- New Haven: M. Steinert & Sons, c1907., 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 42)
      For voice and piano.
    - [Yale!, Yale!, Yale!; arr.] Yale, Yale, Yale: partitura per banda / by Enrico Batelli., 1907; 1 ms. score (9 p.); 33 cm. (Box 2, Folder 43)
      Ms. in ink and pencil.
      Arr. for band.
      At end: Fine li 11-9/1907, L. Pepitta [?]
    - [Yale!, Yale!, Yale!; arr.] Yale!, Yale!, Yale! / by E. Batelli., 32 ms. parts (33 p. total); 31 & 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 44)
      Combination of band and orchestra parts, presumably with overlap of winds and brass.
      Includes ms. title page listing orchestration.
    - [Yale!, Yale!, Yale!; arr. Chorus parts] Yale! Yale! Yale!: a song of New Haven / Ella Wheeler Wilcox - Batelli., 4 ms. parts (6 p. total); 32 & 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 45)
      Parts for SA and TB, with duplicate SA parts.
    - [Zuccaro e beleno] Zuccaro e beleno / versi di Michele Del Prete; musica di Enrico Batelli., 1896; 1 ms. score (8 p.); 33 cm. (Box 2, Folder 46)
      On tp: Caserta, 12 Gennaio 1896.
    - [Sketches], 5 ms. p. of music; various sizes. (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Music by Other Composers, Arranged by Batelli, 1900-1917; Sub-Series I.B
    - [When Irish eyes are smiling] When Irish eyes are smiling / lyric by Chauncey Olcott and Geo. Graff, Jr.; music by Ernest R. Ball. -- New York: M. Witmark, c1912., Ball, Ernest R., 1878-1927; 1 score (4 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - [When Irish eyes are smiling; arr.] Refrain of When Irish eyes are smiling / mixed chorus arrang. by Enrico Batelli., Ball, Ernest R., 1878-1927; 1 ms. choral score (1 p.) + 4 ms. parts (4 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Ms. in ink and colored pencil.
      Arr. by Batelli for chorus (SATB) and strings.
      Parts for vlnI, vlnII, vla, vc.
      For separate chorus parts, see: Van Alstyne, Egbert, 1882-1951. [Because you're Irish; arr.] [2/57]
      String parts for My Wild Irish Rose on verso.
    - [Marche triomphale, op.91; arr.] Marche triomphlae, op. 91: pour deux pianos concertants / A. Goria. – Milan; chez Flucca, [ca. 1900], Goria, A., 1823-1860; 27 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 49)
      Pl. no.: 11484
      Originally for 2 pianos, arr. by Batelli for 3 pianos.
      Published parts for pno1 and pno2, Batelli holograph part for pno3.
      At end of holograph part: New Haven, Conn., 9 Settembre 1900.
    - [Eileen. Irish have a great day to-night; arr.] Eileen: finale, act III / Victor Herbert., Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924; 4 ms. parts (12 p. total); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 50)
      Arr. by Batteli for chorus (SATB) and string quartet.
    - [Eileen. Irish have a great day to-night; arr. Chorus parts] The Irish have a great day to-night / by Victor Herbert; arrang. by E. Batelli., Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924; 4 ms. parts (24 p. total); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 51)
      Choral parts for SATB, in duplicate copies.
    - [Ave Maria; arr.] Ave Maria / by Percy B. Kahn; orchestrated by E. Batelli., Kahn, Percy B., 1880-; 4 ms. parts (10 p. total); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 52)
      Originally for voice and piano, arr. by Batelli for voice and strings.
      Parts for vlnI, vlnII, vc, b.
    - [My wild Irish rose; arr.] My wild Irish rose / by Olcott; refrain arrang. for mixed quartet by Enrico Batelli., Olcott, Chauncey, 1858-1932; 1 ms. choral score (3 p.) + 2 ms. parts (8 p.); 28 & 16 x 25 cm. (Box 2, Folder 53)
      Ms. in ink.
      Chorus parts for SA and TB.
      For string parts, see verso of parts for When Irish eyes are smiling [2/48]
    - [Irish minstrels; arr.] Irish minstrels / arrang. by W. Rhys-Herbert; arrng. for strings by E. Batelli., Rhys-Herbert, W. (William), arr.; 4 ms. parts (12 p.); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 54)
      Arr. by Batelli for chorus and strings.
    - [Echoes from Ireland] Echoes from Ireland: selection of Irish airs / selected and arranged by George Rosey. – New York: Jerome H. Remick, c1907., Rosey, Geo.; 9 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 55)
      Arr. for piano, lyrics appear above the stave.
      Batelli's annotations in pencil and colored pencil.
    - [Echoes from Ireland; arr.] Echoes from Ireland: selection of Irish airs / selected and arranged by Enrico Batelli., Rosey, Geo.; 5 ms. p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 55)
      Arr. for piano, based on Geo. Rosey's Echoes from Ireland.
    - [Pirates of Penzance. Poor wandering one!; arr.] Air - Mabel and chorus: [from] The pirates of Penzance by Gilbert [and] Sullivan / arranged... by Enrico Batelli., Sullivan, Arthur, 1842-1900; 1 ms. score (11 p.) + 5 ms. parts (15 p.); 32 & 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 56)
      Arr. for voice, chorus (SA), fl, vlnI, vlnII, vla, vc, b.
      Lacks separate flute part.
      Score lacks text.
    - [Because you're Irish] Because you're Irish / lyric by Gustave Kahn; music by Egbert Van Alstyne. – New York: Jerome H. Remick, c1917., Van Alstyne, Egbert, 1882-1951; 1 score (5 p.); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - [Because you're Irish; arr.] Because you're Irish / lyric by Gustave Kahn; music by Egbert Van Alstyne; four-part chorus arranged by E. Batelli., Van Alstyne, Egbert, 1882-1951; 1 ms. vocal score (4 p.) + 5 ms. parts (8 p. total); 32 & 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 57)
      Arr. by Batelli for voice, chorus (SATB), and strings.
      Chorus parts include When Irish Eyes are Smiling [on verso]
    - [National anthems; arr.] National hymns / arrang. by Enrico Batelli., 10 ms. parts (24 p. total); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 58)
      Parts for fl, cl, cornet, tbn, pno, vlnI, vlnII, vla, vc, b.
      Composition includes sections labeled: Belgium, France, Russia, England, United-States.
      Various creators.
  - Music by Other Composers, 1889-1902; Sub-Series I.C
    - [Ripeti a me] Ripeti a me: duettino per mezzo soprano e baritono / di Luigi Badia., Badia, Luigi, 1819?-1899; 1 ms score (6 p.); 33 cm. (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - [Ripeti a me] Ripeti a me: duettino [per] mezzo-soprano e baritono / by Luigi Badia., Badia, Luigi, 1819?-1899; 1 ms score (4 p.); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 59)
      Voice parts only, lacks accompaniment.
    - [Amami!] Amami!: romanza / musica del maestro L. Denza., Denza, Luigi, 1846-1922; 1 ms score (7 p.); 30 cm. (Box 2, Folder 60)
      On tp: Leito Gennaro, copista.
    - [Tu!] Denza, Luigi. Tu!: romanza / musica del maestro L. Denza; [text by] G. Gloag., Denza, Luigi, 1846-1922; 1 ms. score (9 p.); 30 cm. (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - [Lacreme amare!] Lacreme amare!: orazione / versi di S. Si Giacomo; musica di E. De Leva., De Leva, Enrico, 1867-1955; 1 ms. score (6 p.); 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - [Vecchio mistero] Vecchio mistero / versi di Nicola Misari; musica de Enrico De Leva., De Leva, Enrico, 1867-1955; 1 ms. score (4 p.); 31 cm. (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - [Andante e fuga] Andante e fuga: per quartetto (corda) / di Paolo Serrao., Serrao, Paolo, 1830-1907; 1 ms. score (23 p.); 33 cm. (Box 2, Folder 64)
      For string quartet.
      Includes line for contrabasso ad libitum for performance by string orchestra.
    - [Berceuse, piano] Berceuses per pianoforte / di Paolo Serrao. – Sassari: Edizioni Michele Sini, 1897., Serrao, Paolo, 1830-1907; 5 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 2, Folder 65)
      Pl. no.: 89
    - [Elegia] Elegia: per violino con accompagnamento di pianoforte / di Paolo Serrao. – Napoli: Raffaele Izzo, [ca. 1900], Serrao, Paolo, 1830-1907; 1 score (6 p.) + 1 part (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 66)
      Pl. no.: 1299
    - [Mazurkas, piano, no. 1, B minor] Ia. mazurka in si minore / Paolo Serrao. – Napoli: Raffaele Izzo, [ca. 1900], Serrao, Paolo, 1830-1907; 5 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 67)
      Pl. no.: 1488
    - [Mazurkas, piano, no. 2, A-flat major] IIa. mazurka in la [bemolle] / Paolo Serrao. – Napoli: Raffaele Izzo, [ca. 1900], Serrao, Paolo, 1830-1907; 5 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 67)
      Pl. no.: 1489
    - [Pensiero elegiaco] Pensiero elegiaco per pianoforte / di Paolo Serrao. – Napoli: Raffaele Izzo, [ca. 1900], Serrao, Paolo, 1830-1907; 3 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 68)
      Pl. no.: 1381
    - [Salve Regina, no. 2. Vocal score] 2da Salve Regina: riduzione dall'orchestra / Paolo Serrao. – Napoli: Raffaele Izzo, [ca. 1900], Serrao, Paolo, 1830-1907; 1 vocal score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 69)
      Arr. for voice accompanied by organ or harmonium.
      Pl. no.: 1045
      Ms. notes indicating orchestration.
    - [Tema con variazioni] Tema con variazioni per pianoforte / di Paolo Serrao. – Napoli: Raffaele Izzo, c1902., Serrao, Paolo, 1830-1907; 23 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 70)
      Pl. no.: 1718
    - [Tempo di valzer] Tempo di valzer / Paolo Serrao. – Napoli: Raffaele Izzo, [ca. 1900], Serrao, Paolo, 1830-1907; 5 p. of music; 5 cm. (Box 2, Folder 71)
      Pl. no.: 1700
      Inscribed to Batelli by the composer.
    - [Waltzes, piano, B-flat] Waltzer in si [bemolle] per pianoforte / Paolo Serrao. – Sassari: Edizioni Michele Sini, [ca. 1900], Serrao, Paolo, 1830-1907; 7 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 2, Folder 72)
      Pl. no.: 90
    - [Auguri felicissimi] Auguri felicissimi: valtzer per pianoforte / di Domenico Sposato. – Napoli: Giannini, [ca. 1889], Sposato, Domenico; 7 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - [Sunt lagrime rerum] Sunt lagrime rerum: petit morceau pour piano / par S. Ursini-Scuderi. – [S.l.]: l'Auteur, [ca. 1900], Ursini-Scuderi, S.; 4 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 74)
      Pl. no.: 46
      Inscribed to Batelli.
    - [Addio. Vocal score] L'addio: duettino per mezzo-sop. e baritono / parole di G. Sesto Giannini; music di E. Viceconte; rid. di E. Batelli., Viceconte, E.; 1 ms. vocal score (8 p.); 33 cm. (Box 2, Folder 75)
      Arr. for voices and piano.
    - [Rosellina bianca] Rosellina bianca: polka per pianoforte / di Giuseppe Vitaliti., Vitaliti, Giuseppe; 3 ms. p. of music / 31 cm. (Box 2, Folder 76)
- Biographical Materials, 1907-1944; Series II
  - Programs, 1917-1935 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - 1917 February 11. Opera and concert benefit of St. John's R. C. Church (25 p.)
    - 1926 March 14. St. Patrick's concert, St. John's R. C. Church (1 p.)
    - 1927 March 20. St. Patrick's concert, St. John's R. C. Church (1 p.)
    - 1929 April 8. Reception and testimonial dinner tendered to Dr. William F. Verdi (14 p.)
    - 1932 April 16. Dinner musical program in honor of Cavalier Joseph C. Johnson (4 p.)
    - 1932 May 26. Piano recital given by students of William Vincent Batelli (3 p.)
    - 1935 March 17, St. Patrick's concert, St. John's R. C. Church (1 p.)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1929-1944 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - April, 1929, 5 p.
    - August, 1944, 3 p.
  - Proposed Constitution and By-Laws for State Teachers' Assn., Oct. 9, 1933.; Typescript (6 p.); 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Photograph post card of the opera stage in Batelli Studio
    - Photocopy of Batelli advertisement in the New Haven Directory, 1908
    - ALS from Vittorio Gregori to Batelli, Providence, RI, 6-3-08
    - Le ultime compositioni del Maestro Maurizio Cattaneo (Milano: Guidici & Strada, ca. 1907), 29 p.